Guide to the Lincoln Collection, American Historical Portraits 19th-20th centuries
University of Chicago Library
- Series I: Individual Portraits
  - Portraits, Mead to Myers, Meade, George G., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Meagher, Thomas F., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Meigs, M.C., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Meredith, Solomon, Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Merriam, ?, Comm. U.S.N. Merrill, Lewis, Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Merritt, Wesley, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Miles, Nelson A., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Miller, Madison, Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Milroy, Robert H., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Mitchell, Donald G., Author Mitchell, Ormsby M., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Mitchell, Robert B., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Moffitt, Stephen, Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Monroe, James, President Montgomery, ?, Comm. U.S.N. Montgomery, Richard, Soldier (Revolution) Morgan, Daniel, Soldier (Revolution), A Morgan, Edwin D., Maj. Gen. U.S.A., Gov. of N.Y. Morgan, George W., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Morgan, John H., Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Morrell, George. W., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Morris, G.A., Commandant U.S.A. Morris, Gouverneur, Statesman, diplomat Morris, Robert, Jurist Morris, T.A., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Morrow, Henry, A., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Morton, James St. Clair, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Morton, Oliver P., Gov. of Indiana Mosby, John, C.S.A. Mott, Gresham, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Moultrie, William, General (Revolution) Mower, Joseph A., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Mudge, William S., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Mulligan, James A., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Myers, Albert J., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Portraits, Nagle to Otis, Nagle, James, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Negley, ?, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Negley, James S., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Nelson, William., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Newton, John, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Nichols, Francis T., Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Nichols, William. A., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Nugent, Robert, Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Oglesby, Richard, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Oliphant, Samuel D., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Ord, Edward O.C., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Orme, William W., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Orr, W.E., 1st Lieutenant, U.S.A. Otis, James, Politician (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Portraits, Paine to Powell, Paine, William H., Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Palmer, Innis, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Palmer, John M., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Palmer, J.S., Admiral U.S.N. Parke, John G., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Patterson, Robert, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Paul, Gabriel R., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Paulding, Hiram, Rear Admiral U.S.N. Pearson, Alfred L., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Pegram, John, Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Pelouse, Louis H., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Pemberton, John C., Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Pender, William D., Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Pennypacker, Galusha, Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Penrose, William H., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Perry, Oliver Hazard, Naval officer Phelps, John W., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Pickett, Geo. E., Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Pierce, Byron R., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Pierce, Franklin, President Pike, Albert, Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Pillow, Gideon T., Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Pinckney, Charles C., Soldier, statesman Pinkney, William, Statesman, diplomat Pleasonton, Alfred, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Poe, Edgar Allan, Writer Poe, Orlando M., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Polk, James K., President Pomeroy, S.C., Senator from Kansas Pope, John, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Porter, Andrew, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Porter, David, Naval officer Porter, David D., Rear Admiral Porter, Fitzjohn, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Porter, W.D., Comm. U.S.N. Potter, Joseph H., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Potter, Robert B., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Powell, John W., Maj. U.S.A. (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Portraits, Pratt to Quitman, Pratt, Calvin E., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Prentiss, Benj. M., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Prescott, William H., Historian Preston, John S., Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Preston, William, Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Price, Sterling, Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Prince, Henry, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Prnyn, Charles, U.S. Navy Putnam, Israel, General (Revolution) Putnam, William Lowell Quimby, Isaac F., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Quitman, John Anthony, Lawyer, soldier (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Portraits, Ramsey to Rutledge, Ramsey, Alex, Gov. of Minn. Ransom, Thomas E.G., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Raum, Green B., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Rawlins, John A., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Reno, Jesse L., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Revere, Paul, Silversmith, patriot Reynolds, John F., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Richardson, Israel B., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Ricketts, James B., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Ringold, Dadwalader, Read Admiral U.S.N. Roberts, Charles W., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Robinson, James J., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Robinson, John C., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Rodes, Robert E., Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Rogers, John, Comm. U.S.N. Rodman, Isaac P., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Roosevelt, Franklin D., President Roosevelt, Theodore, President Rosecrans, William S., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Ross, Leonard F., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Rousseau, Lovell H., Brit. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Rowan, Stephen C., U.S.N. Ruffin, Ed. Rutledge, John, Statesman, jurist (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Portraits, Sanborn to Shepley, Sanborn, John B., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Sandford, Charles. W., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Saulsbury, Willard, Senator Saunders, Aunt Sally, Rutledge family Saxton, Rufus, Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Schenck, Robert C., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Schoepf, Albin, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Schofield, John M., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Schurz, Carl, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Schuyler, Phillip, Soldier (Revolution) Scott, Robert K., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Scott, Winfield, Lt. Gen. U.S.A. Sedgwick, John, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Semmes, Raphael, Rear Admiral U.S.N., Serrell, Edward W., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Sewall, Frederick D., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Seward, William E., Secretary of State Shablona, Indiana Shaler, Alexander, Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Shelton, Charles S. or L.A., General U.S.A. Shepley, George F., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Portraits, Sheridan to Shubrick, Sheridan, Philip H., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Sherman, Roger, Statesman Sherman, William T., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Shields, James, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Shoup, Francis A., Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Shubrick, Wm. B., Rear Admiral U.S.N. (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Portraits, Sickles to Starkweather, Sickles, Daniel E., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Sidell, William H., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Sigel, Franz, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Sigourney, Lydia Huntley, Author Slemmer, Adam J., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Slocum, Henry W., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Slough, John B., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Smith, Caleb B., Secretary of Interior Smith, Charles F., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Smith, E. Kirby, Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Smith, Gustavus, Gen. U.S.A. Smith, John E., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Smith, Joseph, Rear Admiral U.S.N. Smith, Thomas Kilby, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Smith, William F., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Smyth, Thomas A., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Spear, Ellis, Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Speed, James, Attorney General U.S.A. Spinner, F.E., Treasurer of U.S.A. Sprague, Augustus B.R., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Sprague, William, Brig. Gen. U.S.A., Gov. of R.I. Stafford, Leroy, Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Stahel, Julius H., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Stanley, David S., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Stanton, Edwin M., Sec. of War Stark, John, Soldier (Revolution) Starkweather, John C., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Portraits, Steedman to Sykes, Steedman, James B., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Steele, Frederick, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Stephens, Alexander H., Vice-President C.S.A. Stevens, Isaac I., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Stevens, Thaddeus, Congressman from Penn. Stevenson, Thomas, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Stewart, Charles, Rear Admiral Stiles, Israel, Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Stone, Charles P., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Stoneman, George, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Storer, George W., Rear-Admiral U.S.N. Story, Joseph, Jurist, A Streight, Abel D., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Stringhman, S.H., Rear-Admiral U.S.N. Strong, William E., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Sturgis, Samuel D., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Sumner, Charles, Senator (Mass.) Sumner, Edwin V., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Surratt, Mary E., Lincoln assassin Sweeny, Thomas W., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Sweitzer, N.B., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Sykes, George, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Portraits, Taney to Tyndale, Taney, R.B., Chief Justice Taylor, Z., Maj. Gen.; President Terry, Alfred H., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Thayer, John M., Col., Brig., & Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Thomas, Byron, Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Thomas, George H., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Thomas, Lorenzo, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Thompson, Smith, Jurist Tillson, John, Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Tod, David, Gov. of Ohio Todd, John B.S., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Toombs, Robert, Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Torbert, Alfred T.A., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Townsend, Edward D., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Tracy, Benjamin F., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Trenchard, Stephen D., Rear Admiral U.S.N. Trumball, Lyman, Senator from Ill Twiggs, David E., Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Tyler, Dan, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Tyler, John, President Tyler, Robert O., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Tyndale, Hoctor, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Portraits, Underwood to Von Steinwehr, Underwood, John Curtis, Jurist Upton, Emory, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Usher, John P., Secretary of Interior Van Allen, James H., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Van Buren, Martin, President Vandever, William, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Vandorn, Earl, Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Van Vliet, Stewart, Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Viele, Egbert L., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Vincent, Strong, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Vincent, Thomas M., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Von Steinwehr, Adolph, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Portraits, Wade to Whittier, Wade, Benj. F., Senator (Ohio) Wadsworth, James S., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Waggoner, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Wagner, Louis, Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Walcutt, Chas. C., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Walker, Henry H., Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Walker, R. Idndsey, Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Wallace, Lew, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Wallace, W.H.L., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Ward, Durbin, Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Ward, J.H.H., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Ward, J.O., Commander U.S.N. Ward, William T., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Warren, G.K., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Warren, Joseph, Physician, patriot Washburn, C.C., Governor of Wisconsin Washburn, Israel, Governor of Maine Washburne, Elihu B., Representative (Ill.) Washington, George, President Weber, Max, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Webster, Daniel, Statesman Welles, Gideon, Secretary of Navy U.S.N. Wessells, Henry W., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Wheeler, Joseph, Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Whipple, Amiel W., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Whipple, Wm. D., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Whitaker, Walter C., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. White, Julius, Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Whiting, W.H.C., Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Whittier, John G., Poet, Abolitionist (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Portraits, Wickham to Zook and miscellaneous unknowns, Wickham, Wm. C., Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Wilcox, Cadmus M., Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Wilcox, Orlando B., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Wilkes, Charles, Rear Admiral U.S.N. Williams, Alpheus S., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Williams, John S., Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Wilson, Henry, Senator (Mass.); Vice-Pres. Wilson, James H., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Wilson, William, Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Wilson, Woodrow, President Winslow, John A., Commander U.S.N. Winthrop, Theodore, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Wise, Henry Alex, Brig. Gen. C.S.A Wistar, Isaac, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Witcher, John S., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Withers, Jones M., Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Wood, Fernando, Congressman (N.Y.) Wood, Thomas J., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Woods, Chas. R., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Wool, John E., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Wright, Horatio G., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Yates, Richard, Governor of Ill. Yeadon, Richard, Lawyer, editor Zook, Samuel K., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Miscellaneous card photos, unknown Unknown (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Portraits, Unidentified and Illegible, Unknown (Box 6, Folder 38)
- Series II: Group Portraits
  This series is composed of engravings and lithographs of group portraits. The subjects of these groups include Union and Confederate Officers and soldiers as well as Presidential portraits.
  - Group Portraits, Union Officers:, General Nelson Miles and Staff, Lieutenant General Winfield Scott (seated) with Francis C. Barlow, and Generals John Gibbon and David B. Birney, Ulysses S. Grant and Company, 1864; General Philip H. Sheridan and Cavalry Generals, Union Officers, Ulysses S. Grant with General John A. Rawlins and Colonel T.S. Bowers, 1865; Incidents of the War: Major Generals Pleasanton and Custer, 1863; General George G. Meade and Staff, General Robert B. Potter and Staff, 1864; General Edward Ferrero and Officers at the Generals Headquarters, Petersburg, Va; Group Portrait of Union Generals, Captains, and Colonels; Major General Wesley Merritt and Staff; General Birney and Officers (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Union Officers, Group Portraits: Union Naval Officers, Major Generals, Naval Combat of the Monitor and Merimack with Naval Officers, Major General Thomas and Officers of Staff, Union Generals, Brig. General Van Cleve and Officers of Staff, Officers of Our Navy, 1861; Major General Rosecran’s Chief Officers of Staff; Generals of our Army, 1861; Our Cavalry Leaders; The Defenders of Our Union; Union Generals (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Confederate Officer’s Portraits:, Lieutenant and Major Generals portrait, General Robert E. Lee and Officers, General Joseph E. Johnson and officers, Enemies of our Union, Officers of the C.S. Army and Navy (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Group Portraits of United States Presidents:, George Washington family portrait, Presidents of the United States (Box 6, Folder 42)
- Series III: Oversize Portraits
  This series is composed of lithograph and engraved portraits of historical American figures. The materials housed here are divided into two subseries according to the portrait’s size. Subseries 1 houses individual portraits and Subseries 2 group portraits. Please note that there are additional portraits of some historical figures in BOXes 1-3 housed in this series.
  - Subseries 1: Individual Oversize Portraits
    - Portraits, Adams to Cleveland, Adams, John, President Biography Adams, John Q. President Biography Arthur, Chester, President Biography Barton, William E. Lincoln Scholar Beecher, Henry Ward, Clergyman, Abolitionist Buchanan, James, President Biography Cleveland, Grove, President Biography (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Portraits, Douglas to Hayes, Douglas, Stephen A., Senator Ellsworth, Elmer E., Col Fillmore, Millard, President Biography Foster, Stephen C., Songwriter Garfield, James A., President Biography (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Ulysses S. Grant, Grant, Ulysses S., President Biography, portrait engraving, photograph on horse, and painting (See also Folder 48) (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Portraits, Hancock to Johnson, Hancock, Winfield S., President nominee Harrison, Benjamin, President Biography Harrison, William H., President Biography Hayes, Rutherford B., President Biography Jackson, Andrew, President Biography Jefferson, Thomas, President Biography Johnson, Andrew, President Biography (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Portraits Logan to Scott, Logan, John A., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. McClellan, George B., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. McKinley, William, President Biography Madison, James, President Biography Monroe, James, President Biography Pierce, Franklin, President Biography Polk, James K., President Biography Roosevelt, Theodore, President Biography Scott, Winfield, Gen, Comm, U.S.A Army (See also (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Portraits, Stanton to Wilson, Stanton, Edwin M., Sec. of War Taft, William H., President Biography Taylor, Zachary, President Biography Tyler, John, President Biography Van Buren, Martin, President Biography Washington, George, President Biography Wilson, Woodrow, President Biography (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Subseries 2: Group Oversize Portraits
    - Portraits, Grant, Ulysses S., Gen. President Scott, Winfield, Gen. Comm. U.S.A Army (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - Portraits of Presidents and Officials, The Offering of the Carriers of the Press to their Patrons, 1862 Presidents of the United States During the First Century of the Republic, Portrait, date unknown Col. Louis Blenker and First German Rifle Regiment, date unknown The Might of the Republic, 1866 In Remembrance of the One Hundredth Anniversary of the Independence of the United States, 1867 First in War, First in Peace, and first in the hearts of his countrymen: Panorama of Washington, date unknown United States Military Record, 1863 (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - President and Other Group Portraits, Our Presidents: 1789-1881 Our Presidents, date unknown The Commanders-in-Chief of the Grand army of the Republic: 1866-1900 The Commanders-in-Chief of the Grand army of the Republic, date unknown (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - Personal Group and Family Portraits, George Washington and Family, date unknown Gen. U.S. Grant and Family, 1867 Lincoln scholars (Rosenfels, Judge Horner, Barton, Emmanuel Hertz, Oliver Barrett, Jane Hamand, Mrs. Hurd, R. Oakleaf, Eleanor Gridley, Julia Taft Bayne), date unknown Home From Andersonville: Blessed are they that suffer for righteousness sake, 1865 Home on a Furlough: To the Loyal Mothers, Wives, and Daughters of our country, 1864 (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - Unidentified Photographs (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Subseries 3: Addenda
    - Presidential Masquerade, 1880 (Folder Ovrz1)
    - Gen’l W.T. Sherman, 1890 (Folder Ovrz2)
    - The Commanders-in-Chief of the Grand Army of the Republic 1866-1900, 1900 (Folder Ovrz3)